When I was a young officer, they told me
عندما كنت ضابطا شابا، قيل لي،
to follow my instincts,
بأن أتبع غريزتي،
to go with my gut,
بأن أتبع حدسي،
and what I've learned
لكن ما تعلمته كان أن
is that often our instincts are wrong.
الحدس غالبا ما يكون مخطئا.
In the summer of 2010,
في صيف 2010،
there was a massive leak of classified documents
حصل تسريب هائل لوثائق سرية
that came out of the Pentagon.
كان مصدرها البنتاغون.
It shocked the world,
صدم هذا الأمر العالم،
it shook up the American government,
هز الحكومة الأمريكية،
and it made people ask a lot of questions,
وحمل الناس على طرح أسئلة كثيرة،
because the sheer amount of information
لأن كمية المعلومات
that was let out, and the potential impacts,
التي سُرِّبت،وتداعياتها المحتملة،
were significant.
كانت كبيرة.
And one of the first questions we asked ourselves
وكان أحد الأسئلة التي طرحناها على أنفسنا،
was why would a young soldier have access
لماذا يتم إعطاء ضابط شاب حق الوصول
to that much information?
إلى هذا الكم من المعلومات؟
Why would we let sensitive things
لماذا نترك معلومات حساسة كهذه
be with a relatively young person?
في متناول شخص يافع إلى حد ما؟
In the summer of 2003, I was assigned to command
في صيف 2003، عُيِّنتُ لأقود
a special operations task force,
فرقة مهمة عمليات خاصة،
and that task force was spread across the Mideast
وكانت فرقة هذه المهمة منتشرة في الشرق الأوسط
to fight al Qaeda.
لمكافحة تنظيم القاعدة.
Our main effort was inside Iraq,
كان جهدنا مركزا داخل العراق،
and our specified mission
وكانت مهمتنا المحددة
was to defeat al Qaeda in Iraq.
هي قهر القاعدة في العراق.
For almost five years I stayed there,
بقيت هناك قرابة خمس سنوات،
and we focused on fighting a war
وكان تركيزنا على القتال في حرب
that was unconventional and it was difficult
كانت غير تقليدية وصعبة
and it was bloody
كانت دموية،
and it often claimed its highest price
وغالبا ما يدفع ثمنها غاليا
among innocent people.
الناس الأبرياء.
We did everything we could
فعلنا ما بوسعنا
to stop al Qaeda
لإيقاف القاعدة
and the foreign fighters that came in as suicide bombers
والمقاتلين الأجانب الذين يدخلون ساحة الحرب كانتحاريين
and as accelerants to the violence.
وكمؤججين للعنف.
We honed our combat skills,
شحذنا مهاراتنا القتالية،
we developed new equipment,
طورنا معدات جديدة،
we parachuted, we helicoptered,
استعملنا المناطيد والمروحيات،
we took small boats, we drove, and we walked
ركبنا القوارب الصغيرة، قدنا السيارات، وسرنا،
to objectives night after night to stop
في اتجاه الأهداف، ليلة بعد ليلة، لنوقف
the killing that this network was putting forward.
القتل الذي تقوم به هذه الشبكة.
We bled,
سالت دماؤنا،
we died,
قُتِل زملاؤنا،
and we killed to stop that organization
وقتلنا لنوقف تلك المنظمة
from the violence that they were putting
عن العنف الذي كانت تقوم به
largely against the Iraqi people.
بشكل كبير ضد الشعب العراقي.
Now, we did what we knew,
الآن ، قمنا بما كنا نعرفه حينها،
how we had grown up, and one of the things that we knew,
كيف كبرنا، وكان أحد الأشياء التي تعلمناها،
that was in our DNA, was secrecy.
والتي كانت تسري في عروقنا، هي السرية.
It was security. It was protecting information.
كانت الأمن، كانت حماية المعلومات.
and it was what would protect and keep people safe.
أنها هي من ستحمي الناس وتبقيهم آمنين.
And we had a sense that,
وكنا نفهم أنه،
as we operated within our organizations,
بما أننا كنا نشتغل داخل منظمات،
it was important to keep information
أنه من المهم إبقاء المعلومة
in the silos within the organizations,
في مجموعات داخل المنظمات،
particularly only give information
وبالتحديد إعطاء المعلومات فقط
to people had a demonstrated need to know.
للأشخاص الذين برهنوا على أنهم يحتاجون معرفتها.
But the question often came, who needed to know?
لكن السؤال المطروح دائما: من الذي يحتاج لأن يعرف؟
Who needed, who had to have the information
من الذي احتاجها، من كان عليه أن يعرف
so that they could do the important parts of the job that you needed?
لكي يستطيع القيام بالأجزاء المهمة من العمل الذي تحتاجه؟
And in a tightly coupled world,
وفي عالم متداخل جدا،
that's very hard to predict.
يصعب جدا التكهن بهذا.
It's very hard to know who needs to have information
من الصعب جدا معرفة من يحتاج الحصول على المعلومة،
and who doesn't.
ممن لا يحتاجها.
I used to deal with intelligence agencies,
كنت أتعامل مع وكالات الاستخبارات،
and I'd complain that they weren't sharing enough intelligence,
وكنت أتذمر من أنهم لا يتقاسمون الكثير من الاستخبارات،
and with a straight face, they'd look at me and they'd say,
وكانوا ينظرون إلي بوجه واجم، قائلين،
"What aren't you getting?" (Laughter)
"مالذي لم يصلك؟" (ضحك)
I said, "If I knew that, we wouldn't have a problem."
فأجيب: "لو كنت أعلم، لما كانت لدينا أية مشكلة."
But what we found is we had to change.
لكن ما اكتشفناه، هو أنه علينا أن نتغير.
We had to change our culture about information.
كان علينا أن نغير ثقافتنا بشأن المعلومات.
We had to knock down walls. We had to share.
كان علينا أن نزيل الحواجز، كان علينا أن نتقاسم.
We had to change from who needs to know
كان علينا أن نغير السؤال من: من عليه أن يعرف
to the fact that who doesn't know,
إلى : من ليس عليه أن يعرف،
and we need to tell, and tell them as quickly as we can.
علينا أن نخبرهم، وأن نفعل بأسرع ما يمكن.
It was a significant culture shift for an organization
كان تغييرا كبيرا في ثقافة منظمة
that had secrecy in its DNA.
كانت السرية تجري في عروقها.
We started by doing things, by building,
بدأنا بالقيام بأشياء، بالبناء،
not working in offices,
ليس بالعمل داخل المكاتب،
knocking down walls, working in things we called
إزالة الحواجز، والعمل على أشياء سميناها
situation awareness rooms,
غرف الوعي بالأوضاع،
and in the summer of 2007,
وفي صيف 2007،
something happened which demonstrated this.
حصل أمر أكد هذا.
We captured the personnel records
حصلنا على سجلات الموظفين
for the people who were bringing foreign fighters
الذين كانوا يجلبون المقاتلين الأجانب
into Iraq.
إلى العراق.
And when we got the personnel records, typically,
وعندما توصلنا بسجلات الموظفين، في العادة،
we would have hidden these,
كنا لنقوم بإخفائها،
shared them with a few intelligence agencies,
تقاسمها مع بعض الوكالات الاستخباراتية،
and then try to operate with them.
وبعد ذلك نشتغل عليها.
But as I was talking to my intelligence officer,
لكن في حديثي مع ضابط الاستخبارات في فريقي،
I said, "What do we do?"
قلت، "مالذي سنفعله الآن؟"،
And he said, "Well, you found them." Our command.
قال : "حسنا،أنت من وجدها". سيدي.
"You can just declassify them."
"يمكن أن تجعلها علنية."
And I said, "Well, can we declassify them?
قلت" هل يمكن أن نجعلها علنية؟
What if the enemy finds out?"
ماذا لو علم العدو بشأنها؟"
And he says, "They're their personnel records."
قال: "إنها معلوماتهم الشخصية"
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So we did,
وكذلك فعلنا،
and a lot of people got upset about that,
وقد أثار هذا الأمر غضب الكثيرين،
but as we passed that information around,
لكننا تداولنا هذه المعلومات فيما بيننا،
suddenly you find that information is only of value
وفجأة تكتشف أن المعلومة تصبح ذات قيمة فقط
if you give it to people who have the ability
حين تعطيها للناس الذين لديهم القدرة
to do something with it.
على استعمالها.
The fact that I know something has zero value
ما أعرفه هو أن الشيء يصبح غير ذي قيمة
if I'm not the person who can actually
إن لم أكن الشخص المناسب الذي يستطيع
make something better because of it.
صنع شيء أفضل باستعماله.
So as a consequence, what we did was
وبالتالي، ما قمنا به كان
we changed the idea of information,
أن غيرنا فكرتنا عن المعلومة،
instead of knowledge is power,
بدلا من شعار المعرفة قوة،
to one where sharing is power.
إلى : المشاركة قوة.
It was the fundamental shift,
كان هذا تغييرا جذريا،
not new tactics, not new weapons,
لم يكن تنظيما حربيا أو سلاحا جديدا،
not new anything else.
لم يكن أي شيء جديد آخر.
It was the idea that we were now part of a team
كانت الفكرة أننا الآن جزء من فريق
in which information became the essential link
حيث تشكل المعلومة الرابط الأساسي
between us, not a block between us.
بيننا جميعا، وليس الحاجز الذي بيننا.
And I want everybody to take a deep breath
وأريد أن يأخذ الجميع نفسا عميقا
and let it out,
ويأخذ الأمور ببساطة،
because in your life, there's going to be information
لأن في حياتكم، ستكون هناك معلومات
that leaks out you're not going to like.
ستتسرب ولن يروقكم الأمر.
Somebody's going to get my college grades out,
سيفضح أحدهم أمر علاماتي في الجامعة،
a that's going to be a disaster. (Laughter)
وسيكون هذا كارثيا. (ضحك)
But it's going to be okay, and I will tell you that
لكن هذا لا يهم، وسأخبركم أنني
I am more scared of the bureaucrat
خائف بشكل أكبر من البيروقراطيين
that holds information in a desk drawer
الذين يحتفظون بالمعلومات في درج مكتب،
or in a safe than I am of someone who leaks,
أو في مكان آمن، أكثر من خوفي ممن يسربها،
because ultimately, we'll be better off if we share.
لأننا في النهاية، سنتقدم بشكل أفضل إذا تشاركنا.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Helen Walters: So I don't know if you were here this morning,
هيلين والترز: لا أعرف إن كنت هنا هذا الصباح،
if you were able to catch Rick Ledgett,
أو أن كنت قد التقطت بعضا مما قاله ريك ليدجت،
the deputy director of the NSA
نائب مدير وكالة الأمن القومي الأمريكية
who was responding to Edward Snowden's talk earlier this week.
في رده على محادثة إدوار سنودن سابقا هذا الأسبوع.
I just wonder, do you think the American government
أتساءل فقط، هل تعتقد أنه على الحكومة الأمريكية
should give Edward Snowden amnesty?
أن تعفو عن إدوارد سنودن؟
Stanley McChrystal: I think that Rick said something very important.
ستانلي ماكريستال : أعتقد أن ريك قال شيئا مهما جدا.
We, most people, don't know all the facts.
نحن، أعني معظم الناس، لا نعرف كل الحقائق.
I think there are two parts of this.
وأعتقد أن هناك جانبين لهذا الأمر.
Edward Snowden shined a light on an important need
ألقى إدوارد سنودن الضوء على حاجة مهمة
that people had to understand.
كان على الناس أن يفهموها.
He also took a lot of documents that he didn't have
أخذ أيضا العديد من الوثائق التي لم تكن لديه
the knowledge to know the importance of,
الدراية الكافية لمعرفة أهميتها،
so I think we need to learn the facts about this case
لذا أعتقد أن علينا أن نعرف الحقائق عن هذا الموضوع
before we make snap judgments
قبل إطلاق أحكام سريعة
about Edward Snowden.
بحق إدوارد سنودن.
HW: Thank you so much. Thank you.
ه.و : شكرا جزيلا لك. شكرا لك.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)